Inderpreet Singh

3706, Avenue De Kent, Montreal, QC H3S 1N3 (514) 910-9179

preetindr4@gmail.com

 $\underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/inderpreet-singh94/}$

https://inderpreet-singh94.github.io/Portfolio/

English Punjabi Hindi

Front-End Web Developer

Profile

Creative front-end web developer dedicated to building and optimizing the performance of user-centric, high-impact websites. I have excellent client and management skills. Action-oriented with strong ability to communicate effectively with technology, executive and business audiences. In my schooling, I worked on several projects like Elite Restaurant Application in PHP, Pong game in JavaScript and Online Shopping Application in C#.

Technical Skills

Operating System	Windows
Programming Language	C, C++, PHP, C#, Java, JavaScript
Structuring Language	HTML5, CSS3, XML
Software	Filezilla, Putty, Excel
Libraries and Framework	JSP, .Net
Database	MySQL, MySQL Workbench
IDE	Visual Studio, VS Code, Eclipse, NetBeans
Design Methodology	MVC, Command
Version Control	Git Hub, Git Bash
HTTP Servers	Apache Tomcat

Education

Web Programming and Technologies, Attestation of College Studies L'institut Supérieur d'informatique - Montreal	Pursing
Master of Computer Applications, Master's Degree Chandigarh Group of Colleges - India	2014 - 2016
Bachelor of Computer Applications, Bachelor's Degree Chandigarh Group of Colleges – India	2011 - 2014

Professional Experience

PHP Web Developer

Sept 2016 to May 2019

Dolphin Head Hunters - Chandigarh, India

- Design web tools plus modules
- Translate detailed design architecture
- Prepare both application level and user level documentation
- Enhance web application
- Provide technical guidance
- Responsible for analyzing complex system requirement
- Responsible to test and debug
- · Ensuring completion of task in a time efficient manner

PHP Web Developer

Jan 2016 to June 2016

Sharp Web Developers Pvt. Ltd. - Chandigarh, India

- Writing of PHP scripts
- Coding to create or modify software
- Troubleshooting any errors or issues
- Creating documentation

Projects

HTML, CSS | Restaurant Website

- In this project I made a static restaurant website.
- I use the various HTML and CSS tags in this website.
- In this project there are images of the dishes with their price.
- Their is a table from which you can book a table or you can submit your complaint to the restaurant staff.
- I develop this website by my own.

Inderpreet Singh

(514) 910-9179

preetindr4@gmail.com

PHP | Restaurant Website

- In this project we made a restaurant web application to order food online.
- A user can see the description or the ingredients of a dish.
- I worked on the part to fetch data from database to the user screen to show the name and the image of the dishes.
- In this project we are a team two developers.

C# | Online Shopping Application

- In this project there are two panels, one is Admin and other is User.
- Admin can Add the new products in the inventory Section and see how many quantity is sold out.
- User can select the item and save it into the cart and placed the order.
- I worked on the user section. User can see the product and add the products to the cart then user can proceed to the checkout page.
- In the project we are a team of three developers.

React.js | Search a music

- In this project the user can search the song as their choice from Front-end then searched track is fetched from the internet, and displays on the user screen.
- I worked on the part to save a song in database according to the genre
- In this project there is a team of three developers.

Other Experience

Delivery Driver

Apple Express – Montreal

- Loading, transporting, and delivering items
- Reviewing orders
- Customer service
- Following time schedules
- Preparing reports

References available on request